everywhere.
He would put his snout to the ground, give several deep sniffs, and exclaim in a terrible voice,
>> "Snowball! He has been here. I can smell him distinctly."
>> And at the word Snowball, all the dogs let out bloodcurdling growls and showed
their side teeth.
The animals were thoroughly frightened.
It seemed to them as though Snowball was some kind of invisible influence
pervading the air about them and menacing them with all kinds of dangers.
In the evening, Squealer called them together and with an alarmed expression
on his face told them that he had some serious news to report.
>> "Comrades, a most terrible thing has been discovered. Snowball has sold
himself to Frederick of Pinchfield Farm, who is even now plotting to attack us
and take our farm away from us. Snowball is to act as his guide when the attack
begins, but there is worse than that. We had thought that Snowball's rebellion
was caused simply by his vanity and ambition, but we were wrong, comrades.
Do you know what the real reason was?
Snowball was in league with Jones from the very start. He was Jones's secret
agent all the time. It has all been proved by documents which he left behind
him and which we have only just discovered. To my mind, this explains a